<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mat Loughnane</title>
    <description>I like to travel, code and cook...</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 12:41:20 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 12:41:20 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Arranmore Ferry Kiosk</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After a couple of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/hexastudiosco/posts/pfbid02BzRuwGrzaj11KkouRisv7aB3uaKZeBEACybYiB6Kt2RdHkqqp3y9UYkHW22v1Wndl&quot;&gt;teases&lt;/a&gt;, we’re incredibly excited to share our latest project, the Arranmore Ferry self service kiosk. This project is a culmination of months of work (and years or dreaming from Seamus, Louise and myself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little over a year ago I was calling companies asking whether they were able to help me in realising this project. I’m not exaggerating when I say that they laughed down the phone to me, saying that it was not worth their time to work with Hexa, since we’re such a small company… So we built it ourselves. We reached out to the fantastic team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://allsee-tech.com&quot;&gt;AllSee Technologies&lt;/a&gt; - who specialise in interactive displays and started creating inventive code to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com&quot;&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt;’s, the secure digital payment solutions, terminals to faciliate payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then created an application for the kiosk that integrates with the Arranmore Ferry system, ensuring we deliver the latest times, with the latest availability (no double bookings) and collect all your details before printing your ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-kiosk-and-your-journey&quot;&gt;The Kiosk and Your Journey&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you see the kiosk for the first time, you’ll be greeted with a list of the ferry times, showing you the latest time from the pier and the next ferry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clicking any one of these times will select that time and allow you to choose either a return time or book a one way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that we need you to select the number of people who are travelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/code/2023-kiosk/3_5_clicks_arranmore_ferry.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Arranmore Ferry Kiosk takes 5 clicks to book&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-details&quot;&gt;Your Details&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we have your journey, we may need to collect some details, for example it’s useful for the team to know which type of car (and colour) that you’ll be driving on board, the boat. If you want to go green, you can add your email and we’ll issue an e-ticket instead!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/code/2023-kiosk/4_explainer_arranmore_ferry.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Arranmore Ferry Kiosk takes 5 clicks to book&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;payment&quot;&gt;Payment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re ready to pay, hit the big button and you’ll have to use our payment device, just underneath the screen. Tap with your card, phone, watch, Google Pay or Apple Pay or insert your card into the reader at the bottom of the device. Once your payment is accepted, you’ll see your full ticket with QR code on the screen and a ticket will be instantly be printed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you’ve opted to go green, you’ll have received an email instead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve counted, you can have a ticket with &lt;em&gt;5 clicks&lt;/em&gt; of the kiosk and be ready to board the blue ferry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/code/2023-kiosk/5_confirm_pay_sail_arranmore_ferry.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Arranmore Ferry Kiosk takes 5 clicks to book&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;timetables&quot;&gt;Timetables&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also added the option for people to view timetables, just click the button and select the date you wish to view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/code/2023-kiosk/6_timetables_arranmore_ferry.png&quot; alt=&quot;Arranmore Ferry timetables&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;location&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first kiosk location, is on the pier in Burtonport, head into our Self Service booth and start using the kiosk when you land into Burtonport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/code/2023-kiosk/1_intro_arranmore_ferry.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Arranmore Ferry Kiosk is located on Burtonport Pier and is open now&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;download-the-app&quot;&gt;Download the App&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, if you’re running late - or not on the ferry pier - you can download our mobile app at any time and book tickets from your phone or tablet. The app has all the latest times and all the latest info on what’s available in just a few taps. You can even receive notification from the team when there’s changes to ferries or extras running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thank-you&quot;&gt;Thank You&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who made this project possible with their suggestions, ideas, advice and support. In particular I wanted to thank all the Arranmore Ferry team, especially Louise and Seamus for their patience in getting these ideas of the ground and their willingness to innovate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;With this project, I believe The Arranmore Ferry must be one of, if not leading, the charge with digital innovation in Irish ferries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a website that accepts all the latest forms of payment, a fully fledged mobile application with notification, ticketing and stock control. Payment devices on board that link to an admin panel where the team can see tickets in real time and now, a state of the self service kiosk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot wait to see what’s next.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/arranmore-ferry-kiosk/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/arranmore-ferry-kiosk/</guid>
        
        <category>New York</category>
        
        <category>America</category>
        
        
        <category>Ferry</category>
        
        <category>Kiosk</category>
        
        <category>Hardware</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New York</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A trip to New York city in January 2023&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/new-york/PXL_20230123_151331668.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, New York&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/new-york/PXL_20230123_151536871.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, New York&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/new-york/PXL_20230123_195417760.MP.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, New York&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/new-york/PXL_20230124_010109806.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, New York&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/new-york/PXL_20230124_185717792.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, New York&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/new-york/PXL_20230124_211731114.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, New York&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/new-york/PXL_20230124_212151741.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, New York&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/new-york/PXL_20230126_153437150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, New York&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/new-york/PXL_20230126_160427731.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, New York&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/new-york/PXL_20230126_174002037.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, New York&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/new-york/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/new-york/</guid>
        
        <category>New York</category>
        
        <category>America</category>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creamy Tuscan Pasta</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;creamy-tuscan-chicken-pasta&quot;&gt;Creamy Tuscan Chicken Pasta&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a recipe found on instagram by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/kauscooks/&quot;&gt;@kauscooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chicken&quot;&gt;Chicken&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 tsp Paprika
1 tsp Cayenne Pepper or Chilli Powder
1 tsp Garlic Powder
1 tsp Onion Powder
Salt and Pepper to taste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sauce&quot;&gt;Sauce&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Small Red Onion
4 Garlic Gloves chopped
1 Small Red Pepper
250ml Double Cream
1 tsp Paprika
1 tsp Red Chilli Flakes
2 tsp Pepper
1 tsp Salt (to taste)
1/2 Jar of Sundried Tomatoes
40g Cheddar Cheese
2-3 Handfuls of Spinach&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pasta (shells or tubes work best)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;steps&quot;&gt;Steps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butterfly chicken and coat in the spice mix&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add some oil to a pan and cook the chicken through&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the same pan, add the onion, garlic and pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start boiling the pasta&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover in spices and toast for a couple more minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the cream and salt and pepper to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simmer for a few minutes, then add spinach and sundried tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the chedder cheese and some pasta water to emulsify&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve with chicken sliced on top of the pasta.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/creamy-tuscan-pasta/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/creamy-tuscan-pasta/</guid>
        
        <category>Chicken</category>
        
        <category>Savoury</category>
        
        
        <category>Recipes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2022 Hexa Studios Round Up</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of year again - here’s a round up of everything that Hexa Studios shipped this year. It’s been a busy one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;arranmore-ferry-relaunch&quot;&gt;Arranmore Ferry Relaunch&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right at the start of the year - we relaunched the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hexastudios.co/blog/new-arranmore-ferry-mobile&quot;&gt;Arranmore Ferry app&lt;/a&gt; with a completely new User Interface and User Experience (UI/UX). The app, website and API were all given a complete rewrite and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://thearranmoreferry.com/about&quot;&gt;Arranmore Ferry team&lt;/a&gt; were given a whole new admin panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The new Arranmore app features all our dashboard, where you’ll see the latest for todays and tomorrows ferries, any messages from the team about the day or upcoming events will also appear here.
You can view the timetables for the year or pick a date for any day using our date picker too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://directus.hexastudios.co/assets/6d42500b-3fce-4f59-a8bc-022099b4bff6&quot; alt=&quot;The Arranmore Ferry App&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Arranmore Ferry team have some exciting news about a &lt;a href=&quot;https://thearranmoreferry.com/blog/the-new-arranmore-ferry&quot;&gt;brand new ferry&lt;/a&gt; coming in 2023 - so download the app now for the latest news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;seo-árainn-mhór-launch&quot;&gt;Seo Árainn Mhór Launch&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/code/2022-round-up/background.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Seo Árainn Mhór Featured Background&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Spring we launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://seoarainnmhor.com/app&quot;&gt;Seo Árainn Mhór&lt;/a&gt;, a mobile app for the island of Arranmore, Co. Donegal. The app features ‘pages’ which each business owner is able to create and update. Each page features photos, opening times, posts and location maps. Everything a business could need to promote themselves on the island and more importantly how people on the island and visitors cand find all the information they need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Another aspect of the project which was hugely important, was that the Gaeilge language be featured front and centre. You’ll see in screenshots below and in &lt;a href=&quot;https://seoarainnmhor.com/blog/x-post-hexa-seo-arainnmhor-launch&quot;&gt;all marketing materials&lt;/a&gt; that we’ve endevoured to feature it in every screen of the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/code/2022-round-up/app-blue.png&quot; alt=&quot;App screenshots&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seo Árainn Mhór is available now for download.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tory-and-arranmore-get-google-and-apply-pay-support&quot;&gt;Tory and Arranmore get Google and Apply Pay support&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in 2022 I deployed brand new ticketing flows for &lt;a href=&quot;https://toryferry.com/app&quot;&gt;Tory&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://thearranmoreferry.com/&quot;&gt;Arranmore&lt;/a&gt; Ferries. The new ticketing flow employs &lt;a href=&quot;https://stripe.com&quot;&gt;Stripe&lt;/a&gt;’s official flutter implementation which we used to enable Apple Pay and Google Pay in both apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition the updates included a new feature to pull the latest blog data into the app. Download the Tory Ferry app to view the latest &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.toryferry.com/blog/tory-ferry-v6-update&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://directus.hexastudios.co/assets/90ff2ebf-9f41-4cb3-a56c-01009f03a491&quot; alt=&quot;Tory Ferry Promo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;heritage-points-on-seo-árainn-mhór&quot;&gt;Heritage Points on Seo Árainn Mhór&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late August we &lt;a href=&quot;https://seoarainnmhor.com/blog/heritage-points&quot;&gt;launched&lt;/a&gt; a sister project to Seo Árainn Mhór: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scéalóbhéal.com/&quot;&gt;Scéal Ó Bhéal&lt;/a&gt; - a collection of audio stories capturing stories from Arranmore Island told by islanders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The points were all integrated into the Seo Árainn Mhór app where you can listen to the stories in English and Gaeilge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/code/2022-round-up/scealabheal-straight.png&quot; alt=&quot;Promo image for Seo Árainn Mhór update&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;gúrú---remote-mentoring-web-app&quot;&gt;gúrú - remote mentoring web app&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final launch of 2022 came in the form a web app - connecting people to remote working mentors, called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gúrú.work/&quot;&gt;gúrú&lt;/a&gt;. The mission statement is, as stated on the website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;At gúrú we are here to help; by matching expert volunteer mentors with community members looking for their next remote employment opportunity, we help break down the barriers to finding your perfect job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is currently being trialled by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://growremote.ie/arranmore-chapter-new-remote-mentoring/&quot;&gt;growremote.ie&lt;/a&gt; team and we’re working on getting fixes in for them - so stay tuned for more updates soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/code/2022-round-up/guru-meta.png&quot; alt=&quot;Promo image for Seo Árainn Mhór update&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;favourite-tech&quot;&gt;Favourite Tech&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to give credit where it’s due and I employed a lot of new open source technologies this year - keep up to date with my twitter where I try and share all the exciting tech I use. Two in particular were really cool:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;umami&quot;&gt;Umami&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://umami.is/&quot;&gt;Umami analytics&lt;/a&gt; is an open source privacy focused Google Analytics alternative. It’s quick and easy to set up and you can create shareable links for clients individual dashboards. I’ve got all my projects running their analytics using one installation of Umami.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;supabase&quot;&gt;Supabase&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://supabase.io&quot;&gt;Supabase&lt;/a&gt; is the open source Firebase alternative that gives Postgres a really powerful API, with official sdks for JS and Flutter. We’ve used the platform for gúrú, the remote mentoring project we launched this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2023&quot;&gt;2023&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a productive year and I’ve got big plans for 2023. As always let me know if you have any ideas on what I should build next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2022-hexa-round-up/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2022-hexa-round-up/</guid>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
        <category>app</category>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skiing in Sierra Nevada</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;2021 ended with a Spanish holiday including, Sierra Nevada and skiing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/sierra-nevada/PXL_20211210_180922091.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset in Sierra Nevada&quot; /&gt;
Sunset in Sierra Nevada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/sierra-nevada/PXL_20211211_162700087.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skiing in Sierra Nevada&quot; /&gt;
Skiing in Sierra Nevada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/sierra-nevada/PXL_20211211_175100446.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;View from the town looking south&quot; /&gt;
View from the town looking south.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;wider-image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;featured-image lazyimg&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/sierra-nevada/PXL_20211211_151907918.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kinkaku-ji, The Temple of the Golden Pavillion&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kinkaku-ji, The Temple of the Golden Pavillion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/sierra-nevada/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/sierra-nevada/</guid>
        
        <category>Sierra Nevada</category>
        
        <category>Spain</category>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Donegal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A weekend away exploring Donegal after 5K restrictions had lifted on the county. First weekend away in a long time and the weather was amazing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/donegal/IMG_20210424_122856.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, Donegal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/donegal/IMG_20210424_144503.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, Donegal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/donegal/IMG_20210424_151229.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, Donegal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/donegal/IMG_20210425_173056.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, Donegal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/donegal/IMG_20210425_174733.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, Donegal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/donegal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/donegal/</guid>
        
        <category>Doengal</category>
        
        <category>Ireland</category>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simple Butter Chicken Recipe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A simple butter chicken curry recipe modified for two from Josh Weissman’s YouTube Channel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hDjK5C2aoSs&quot; class=&quot;btn badge-primary&quot;&gt;Original Recipe →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;marinade&quot;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;160g full-fat yogurt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10g garam masala&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10g kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 Chicken Breasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;curry&quot;&gt;Curry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;30g vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 white onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2-inch knob of ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 cloves of sliced garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8g paprika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9g ground cumin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;14g garam masala&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10g turmeric powder *optional&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;400g can of crushed tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;160ml water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;240ml heavy cream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;28g unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Salt and pepper to taste&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rice + Corriander&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;marinade-1&quot;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix the yoghurt, garam masala and salt in a bowl&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chop the chicken into 1 inch piece and place and coat in the marinade bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leave to rest covered in cling film for 30 minutes+ (up to overnight)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-curry&quot;&gt;The Curry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a non stick pan heat some vegetable oil over medium / high heat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the chicken to pan to sear - cook it quickly, but not all the way through (yet)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the chicken from the pan and leave to rest for a minute.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dice the onion and finely dice the ginger and add to the pan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the 6 cloves of sliced garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add water to the pot if necessary to get the fond off the bottom.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook for 3 minutes until vegetables or soft.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add all the spices to the mix. Cumin (9g), Garam Masala (14g), Paprika (8g), Tumeric (10g) and cook for a further 2 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the can of tomatoes, then add the water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let it simmer for 5-8 minutes until it’s reduced by 30%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the chicken back to the pan - let it simmer for another 3-5 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the 250ml of cream.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn off the heat and add the 28g butter - keep the curry moving to helpemulsify the butter correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile cook the rice and serve together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/recipes/butter-chicken/bc-prep.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;All the items are prepped&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wider-image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;featured-image lazyimg&quot; src=&quot;assets/images/recipes/butter-chicken/bc-plate.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/simple-butter-chicken/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/simple-butter-chicken/</guid>
        
        <category>Curry</category>
        
        <category>Savoury</category>
        
        
        <category>Recipes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Banana Bread</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A simple but tasty banana loaf bread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cake&quot;&gt;Cake&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;125g butter room temperature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;200g brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 extra-large eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;350g (approx. 5/6) large bananas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;250g flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;topping&quot;&gt;Topping&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoon brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;method&quot;&gt;Method&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven at 180°C and grease a loaf tin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beat the butter (125g) and Brown Sugar (200g) together until light, then add each egg individually.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mash or use a blender to break down the banana bread and add to the mixture. Stir in the vanilla extract too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mix together the flour (250g), baking powder (2 tsp) and cinnamon (1 tsp) then combine the two mixes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the mixture to the loaf tin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine the brown sugar and cinnmon to make the topping and sprinkle on top before putting it in the oven.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leave in the oven for 45 minutes or until a cake tester comes out clean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/recipes/banana-bread/top-view.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The loaf before going into the oven&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wider-image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;display:flex&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&quot;margin: 0 auto&quot; class=&quot;featured-image lazyimg&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/recipes/banana-bread/final-cropped.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The finished product - banana bread&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/banana-bread/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/banana-bread/</guid>
        
        <category>Sweet</category>
        
        <category>Loaf</category>
        
        
        <category>Recipes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Raspberry Ripple Loaf</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A loaf cake of my own design - Raspberry Ripple Loaf Cake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;225g Unsalted Butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;225g Caster Sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;225g Self Raising Flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 Eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tsp Raspberry Flash Frozen Powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;30g Frozen Raspberries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1g Red Food Colouring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;85g Icing Sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/recipes/raspberry-ripple-loaf/IMG_20210312_200439.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Raspberry Ripple Loaf&quot; /&gt;
Raspberry Ripple Loaf straight from the oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;method&quot;&gt;Method&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat the oven to 180°C (160°C Fan).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cream the butter (225g) and sugar (225g) together (I usually stick the button in the microwave to soften it).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the eggs, 1 at a time and continue mixing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the self raising flour (225g).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Separate the mixture into two, add the raspberry powder (3 tsp) and food colour into one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scoop the mixtures alternately and unevenly into a greased and lined 9” loaf tin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use and spoon and lift parts of the mixtures through eachother, don’t mix, you wand the colours to be separate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook for 50 - 55 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drizzle-recipe&quot;&gt;Drizzle Recipe&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blend a small amount of water and the frozen raspberries into a smooth liquid.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sieve the seeds from the mixture into the icing sugar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That’s it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the loaf comes out of the over, poke several holes with your cake tester and pour the drizzle over the top as it cools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wider-image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;!-- &lt;img class=&quot;featured-image lazyimg&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/recipes/raspberry-ripple-loaf/IMG_20210312_212027.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Zooming in on the Raspberry Ripple Loaf&quot;&gt; --&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;featured-image lazyimg&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/recipes/raspberry-ripple-loaf/IMG_20210312_212016.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Zooming in on the Raspberry Ripple Loaf&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/rapberry-ripple-loaf/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/rapberry-ripple-loaf/</guid>
        
        <category>Loaf</category>
        
        <category>Raspberry</category>
        
        
        <category>Recipes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pori and Helsinki</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In September 2019 I travelled to Pori for work and managed a weekend visit to Helsinki. In Pori I was working for Caped Koala’s game, Level Up with students from Sataedu. Helsinki was fantastic too, I even managed a short trip to Suomenlinna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://capedkoala.com/news/levelling-up-our-testing-skills/&quot; class=&quot;btn badge-primary&quot;&gt;Caped Koala’s Blog →&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/helsinki/IMG_20190925_132440.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, Helsinki&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/helsinki/IMG_20190927_182856.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, Helsinki&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/helsinki/IMG_20190927_184529.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, Helsinki&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/helsinki/IMG_20190928_105231.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, Helsinki&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/travel/helsinki/IMG_20190928_134809.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mat Loughnane visiting, Helsinki&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/helsinki/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/helsinki/</guid>
        
        <category>Latvia</category>
        
        <category>Riga</category>
        
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
